Malav Mistry

Washington D.C | +1 (562) 377-4972 | malav345@gmail.com

Profile

A graduate student with master's in computer science and 3+ years of professional experience in software industry, seeking a challenging and rewarding full time opportunity which effectively utilizes my analytical, technical, and interpersonal skills

Technical Skills

- Languages: C#, SQL, T-SQL, HTML, CSS3, XML JavaScript, jQuery, ASP.NET, php, Java
- Frameworks: ASP.NET MVC, REST, AngularJS, Bootstrap, AJAX, JSON
- Tools: GitHub, Visual Studio, NetSuite, JIRA, FileZilla, Mixpanel, Jenkins, AWS, SSMS, Oracle, PowerShell

Education

Master's in Computer Science - Cal State Unv, Long Beach
 Bachelor of Engineering in Information Technology - Mumbai University
 August 2015- December 2016
 August 2011- May 2015

Work Experience

• **Software Developer** – Motionsoft Inc. (Rockville, MD)

November 2019 – Present

- o Developed web application solutions using C# and ASP.NET
- o Developed client-side scripting using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX
- o Designed and implemented database schemas and integrate them with web applications.
- o Analyzed SQL query and Stored Procedures for performance and tuning
- o Analyzed existing systems, reviewed security architectures, and developed engineering solutions that integrate information security requirements to proactively manage information protection
- o Interfaced application with peripheral hardware such as receipt printers, sig pads, payment devices
- Technical Support Engineer II Motionsoft Inc. (Rockville, MD)

 Ju

July 2017 – November 2019

- o Create complex SQL scripts to identify and clean data specific issues to run on Production sites
- o Debug issues to find the error in the application code, fix it and escalate it to Senior Developers for review
- Report code-based issues including data being set into the database incorrectly as well as data being handled incorrectly through code
- o Optimized poor performing SQL scripts and Stored Procedures
- o Managed and maintained AWS database for internal troubleshooting of software issues
- o Technologies: C#, .Net, MVC, Visual Studio, T-SQL, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, AWS
- Web Developer Pronear Inc (Los Angeles, CA)

February 2017 - April 2017

- o Developed and maintained a responsive landing website using HTML5 CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery
- O Used php to validate and store user data in .csv format.
- o Set up tracking to track user events on website
- o Technologies worked with: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, PHP, Mixpanel
- Software Engineer Intern Persistent Computer Services (Mumbai, India) July 2014 July 2015
 - o Collaborated with the Project Manager and development team members to develop high quality product
 - o Applied object-oriented concepts to develop multi-threaded applications.
 - o Worked in a team to create and maintain web applications accessed on desktop environments.
 - o Experience in tuning poor performing scripts
 - Experience in troubleshooting and debugging software issues
 - o Technologies worked with: .Net, C#, Visual Studio, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, SQL